Finding aid to Elizabeth Jane Hellebush papers CA.MS.00356
Smith College Archives
Elizabeth Jane Hellebush papers
1926-1930
Smith College Archives
Hellebush, Elizabeth Jane
CA.MS.00356
0.833 linear feet (2 containers)
These papers contain letters between Elizabeth Jane Hellebush and the Hellebush family as well as other correspondence, along with some newspaper clippings.
Biographical / Historical
Elizabeth Hellebush, Class of 1930, was a member of Phi Beta Kappa. She worked for the New York Daily News until her marriage to MacLellan E. King in 1934. Hellebush lived in New York, Washington DC and Chicago. She moved to Boston after the death of her husband in 1966 and died on January 27, 1980 at Phillips House in Boston.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains primarily letters written by "Betty Jane" to her family (namely her father Charles K. Hellebush, her mother Christine, and her brother Blair). A dedicated correspondent, the collection includes daily and weekly correspondence from the entirety of her first, second, and fourth year at Smith, as well as of her tour of Europe in the summer of 1928. The collection also contains a few letters received by the Hellebush family from other correspondents and assorted newspaper clippings pertaining to Betty Jane.
Index to Letters
Amsterdam, The Netherlands
08/06/1928, 08/08/1928
Anti-Semitism
09/26/1926, 10/03/1926, 10/05/1926, 01/15/1927, 01/20/1927, 05/27/1927, 10/06/1927, 05/26/1928
Balls, Dances, and Social Events
02/17/1927, 03/05/1927, 01/22/1928, 01/30/1928, 02/12/1928, 02/15/1928, 02/17/1928, 02/21/1928, 05/23/1928, 05/26/1928, 01/19/1930, 02/07/1930, 02/13/1930, 02/19/1930, 02/25/1930, 03/06/1930, 03/10/1930, 05/17/1930
Belgium
08/01/1928, 08/02/1928, 08/08/1928
Berlin, Germany
07/29/1928, 08/01/1928
Budapest, Hungary
07/05/1928
Career
05/20/1928, 10/01/1928, 10/15/1929, 10/16/1929, 10/26/1929, 11/29/1929, 12/11/1929, 01/17/1930, 02/03/1930, 02/07/1930, 02/09/1930, 02/19/1930, 02/25/1930, 02/27/1930, 03/06/1930, 03/12/1930, 03/16/1930, 04/01/1930, 04/09/1930, 04/11/1930, 04/15/1930, 04/16/1930
Carlisle, United Kingdom
08/20/1928
Class
10/14/1926, 01/15/1927, 10/19/1927, 11/06/1927
Cologne, Germany
07/31/1928
Commencement
10/01/1929, 01/14/1930, 05/23/1930, 05/27/1930, 06/01/1930, 06/03/1930
Dating
1926-1930
Dresden, Germany
07/26/1928
German Club
11/13/1927, 11/14/1927, 11/25/1927, 12/04/1927, 12/08/1927, 01/22/1928, 02/19/1928, 05/17/1928
Grades
1926-1930
Grasmere, United Kingdom
08/20/1928
International Relations Club
10/25/1926, 10/19/1927, 05/17/1928, 05/23/1928, 12/08/1929, 01/14/1930, 02/13/1930, 03/06/1930
Jordan House
1926-1930
Lemington, United Kingdom
08/14/1928
London, United Kingdom
02/02/1928, 08/14/1928
Mountain Day
10/14/1926, 10/11/1926, 10/14/1927, 10/06/1929, 10/08/1929
Nuremburg, Germany
07/09/1928, 07/15/1928
Paris, France
06/26/1928, 07/01/1928, 17/02/1928, 07/04/1928, 07/09/1928
Phi Beta
05/17/1928, 05/20/1928, 10/06 /1929, 01/19/1930, 02/19/1930, 02/21/1930, 03/14/1930, 03/15/1930, 03/16/1930, 04/13/1930, 04/15/1930
President William Allen Neilson
10/14/1926, 10/28/1926
Racism
10/26/1927, 12/11/1927, 05/28/1927
Rally Day
02/06/1927, 02/20/1927, 02/23/1927, 02/19/1930
Telescopium
05/17/1927, 05/27/1927, 01/22/1928, 04/20/1928, 05/20/1928, 05/06/1928, 05/17/1928
Town-Gown Relations
11/10/1926, 04/21/1927, 11/06/1927, 01/29/1928
Transferring Colleges
01/29/1928, 01/30/1928, 02/01/1928, 02/03/1928, 02/17/1928, 02/21/1928, 01/22/1928
Vacation
1926-1930
Vienna, Austria
07/19/1928, 07/20/1928
Weight
09/26/1926, 09/29/1929, 10/03/1926, 10/05/1926, 10/10/1926, 10/14/1926, 10/20/1926, 10/25/1926, 10/28/1926, 11/01/1926, 02/17/1927, 02/20/1927, 10/02/1927, 05/26/1928, 08/14/1928, 10/06/1929, 10/10/1929, 12/01/1929, 12/16/1929, 12/08/1929, 01/19/1930
Windermere, United Kingdom
08/20/1928
Women's Rights
11/01/1926, 01/28/1927, 02/23/1927
Conditions Governing Access
The records are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Elizabeth Jane Hellebush papers were donated to the College Archives by Prudence King in June 2010.
Smith College--Alumni and alumnae--History--Sources
- Correspondence, September - October 1926 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, November 1926 - January 1927 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, February - March 1927 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, April 1927 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, May - June 1927 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, September - October 1927 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, November - December 1927 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, January - February 1928 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, March - April 1928 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, May - June 1928 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, June 1928 - August 1928 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, September - October 1929 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, November - December 1929 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, January - February 1930 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, March - April 1930 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, May - June 1930 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Letters from Elizabeth Jane Hellebush to parents, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Letters received by Hellebushes from senders other than Elizabeth Jane Hellebush, August 1928; undated (Box 2, Folder 10)